

## SIGFRID STJÄRNHOLM

Physics student & developer

**Weden** Uppsala, Sweden

### linkedin.com/in/ssigfrid

github.com/kladdy



### **CAREER SUMMARY**

As a student at both gymnasial and University level, I have been engaged in various councils related to my studies. Working as a software consultant alongside my studies have yielded me great experience in how projects develop and has also allowed me

### **EDUCATION**

### Master's degree (Master's Programme in Physics)

**Uppsala University** 

**particle physics** 

**INTERESTS** 

**Quantum physics** 

Nuclear physics **Simulations** 

Experiments

Open-source

## **SKILLS & TOOLS Software** Python C# / C++ JS / TS / Node.js SQL HTML / CSS LaTeX Git HTTP / DNS Hardware Arduino / Raspberry Pi Computer assembling Circuits

**Uppsala University** 

Other

Giving speeches **Presentations** Structuring work

**Getting things done** Collaborative Independent Responsible

**HOBBIES** 

Mountain hiking Bread baking

Skiing

റ്റ് Cycling

Computer hardware

to test the waters in a large variety of programming paradigms.

2021 - Present

with the course collection of mine I have chosen to put a lot of weight on the experimental aspect of particle physics. **Achievements:** 

Physics track. The programme reinforces the knowledge within fundamental physics, and

A two-year programme at Uppsala University, specializing in the Nuclear and Particle

- Co-author of a paper published in Astroparticle Physics, and author of conference proceedings for two international conferences (ICRC 2021 and ARENA 2022)
- Student representative in the Programme Advisory Board for the Masters's Programme in Physics
- Recipient of the award 'Best student presentation' at The Student Conference in Science and Technology 2021
- Recipient of the scholarship Hallberg, Malin and Ivar, which is awarded to a 'talented' student'

### **Selection of courses (so far):**

**Classical Electrodynamics Accelerators and Detectors** Advanced Particle Physics **Automatic Control I** Fluid Mechanics **Computer Programming II** Electric Measurement Techniques **Electronics I Industrial Management** Solid State Physics F Quantum Field Theory Solid Mechanics Symmetry and Group Theory in Physics **Statistical Methods in Physics** 

physics - from classical mechanics to advanced quantum physics. The programme also

**Achievements:** 

2018 - 2021 A three-year programme at Uppsala University covering a large portion the fundamental

**Bachelor's degree** (Bachelor's Programme in Physics)

 Student representative in the Programme Advisory Board for the Bachelor's Programme in Physics

 Vice Chairman in the Student Faculty Council for Physics students • Recipient of three prices from the Mathematical Society at Uppsala University for

involves plenty of rigour in mathematics and a lot of programming.

- distinctive performance in the courses Geometry and Calculus I, Geometry and Calculus III, and Fourier Analysis Recipient of Melanderhjelm's scholarship from the Faculty of Science and
- Technology at Uppsala University **Selection of courses:**

### **Analytical Mechanics**

Electromagnetic Field Theory **Complex Analysis** Computer Programming I Electromagnetism Geometry and Calculus I, II & III **Elementary Particle Physics** Fourier Analysis Mechanics KF & III Linear Algebra II Mathematical Methods of Physics Mathematical Statistics KF **Medical Physics Nuclear Physics** Ordinary Differential Equations I Physics Project I & II **Quantum Physics** Physics Project with a Research Basis Quantum Mechanics Physics and Finance Scientific Computing KF & II Special Relativity **Statistical Mechanics Thermodynamics Waves and Optics** 

**Gymnasium** (Natural Science Programme) 2015 - 2018

Björknäsgymnasiet

A three-year programme at Björknäsgymnasiet involving the natural sciences.

**Achievements:** 

- Chairman in the Programme Advisory Board for the Natural Science Programme Chairman in the Student Council for Björknäsgymnasiet
- Scholarship from the Natural Science Programme for distinctive performance Attendee of a 2-week long internship at CERN (HSSIP)
- Finalist in Wallenbergs fysikpris (Swedish national physics competition) and competitor in the Nordic-Baltic Physics Olympiad (NBPhO)
- Attendee of Berzeliusdagarna, a weekend-seminar for students interested in chemistry
- Attendee of Rymdforskarskolan, a 2-week programme at Esrange space center

# **ENGAGEMENTS**

Self-employed at Stjärnholm Consulting

Banner carrier for Norrland's nation (Student association in Uppsala)

**1** Test supervisor at the Swedish Scholastic Aptitude Test (Högskoleprovet, SweSAT)

Election worker at the

2022 Swedish general election Hometown ambassador

for Uppsala University

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### 2021 - Present With a part-time employment during the Master's Programme, I have worked as a research

Research assistant and teaching assistant

**Uppsala University** 

involved within the Astroparticle Physics research group, coupled to the Division for High Energy Physics (HEP). I have also worked as a teacher assistant at the Department of Information Technology. **Involvements:** 

assistant at the Department of Physics and Astronomy at Uppsala University. I am

## Teacher assistant during fall 2022 in the course Application-Oriented Deep Learning

- in Physics, a course which introduces machine learning, deep learning, and neural networks with a focus on applications in physics. Research tasks related to using neural networks to reconstruct neutrino properties from radio detector data. The work is to be used for an upcoming detector station at
- the South Pole called IceCube-Gen2 radio, and was a continuation of my bachelor's thesis. Research regarding the use of wind generators and batteries that can handle the extreme cold at the South Pole. The tasks included measuring of generator losses,
- output voltages, as well as battery capacities. • Teaching assistant in Computer Programming II during spring 2022. The course was given in Python, and the tasks included correcting assignments and aiding students with the course material.

## The date is 2022-10-14

**STATISTICS** 

and the time is 22:42:59 Thave lived for

23 yr, 4 mo, 24 d, 10 h, 1 min, 59 s I have donated

21 240 004 060 303 thrombocytes during 36 occasions I have published

visited by 106 people My CV has been downloaded by 12 people

My website has been

3 scientific papers

### 2016 - Present Jolix is an IT consulting company specializing in E-commerce applications. At Jolix, I have

**Software consulting** 

Jolix AB

worked on plenty of projects within varying programming environments. The company

also runs a small electronics store in Boden named pålyset.se, in which I have worked as a clerk. **Projects:** Backend development of a checkout system for organizations using C#, Node.js &

## microservices

- Backend development of a message listener for IoT-devices reporting back to a central hub using Node.js
- Frontend development of a dashboard web application for E-commerce admins **Technologies used:**

Integrating customers to a Storm API in C#

.NET (4.5 & Core) Python Node.js HTML JSON Test-driven development Unit testing Microservices React Redux Swagger

C#

interested in physics. During three intensive days, the students get to partake in laboratory

CSS

Javascript/Typescript

**Event organizer** Lise Meitner-dagarna 2019 - 2021 Lise Meitner-dagarna is a yearly weekend-seminar in Stockholm for high-school students

## experiments, exhibitions and lectures by prominent physicists in a variety of fields. The

social media.

- organizing group consists of 4 members, and about 130 students from all over Sweden attend the event each year.
- Roles: • Head of administration (2019 - 2020): Bookings for hotel, catering, and trips for the whole event. Managing registrations for schools, students, and exhibitors. • Head of communication and marketing (2021): Designs for mailings.

Communication with schools and students. Upkeep of the website. Photography and